Women Against War; Records apap391
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Women Against War Records
2001-2023
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap391
45.54 MB
4.95 cubic ft.
This collection documents the founding, day-to-day operations, and events and projects of Women Against War, an organization based in the Capital Region of New York.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Eleanor Stein donated paper records in 2020. Mickie Lynn and Maud Easter arranged for the donation of the Women Against War Waging Peace blog in 2021. In 2024, Maud Easter donated paper records, the Yahoo Groups email correspondence, and mixed A/V materials, including CDs, DVDs, cassettes, and videocassettes, and Trudy Quaif donated videos she had of interviews with longtime Women Against War members.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are no series.
Historical Note
Women Against War was formed in 2002 by a network of Capital District New York women who mobilized against the United States government's plan to go to war with Iraq. Their first public event was a gathering that took place on the steps of the Legislative Office Building in Albany on December 5, 2002, where the group put out an open call for participants in their Women's Fast for Peace. The Fast for Peace was ultimately a continuous five-month event where each participant fasted for a twenty four hour period and documented the experience in a shared journal. The group's initial focus was on the cost of the Iraq War to women and children, but, since its inception, Women Against War has expanded their focus through projects and events on Iraqi refugees, Iran, Afghanistan, Korea, the Patriot Act, Islamophobia, and U.S. military spending and recruitment at large. They have become a vital participant in the larger national and international peace and justice movement through their various projects and affiliations, advocating for changed U.S. foreign policies through lobbying, leafletting, billboard and yard sign campaigns, traveling exhibits, vigils, media outreach, and educational events. They have collaborated with other prominent peace organizations, including the American Friends Service Committee and Code Pink. In 2006, a sub-group of Women Against War called Grannies for Peace was established, inspired by the New York City based organization Granny Peace Brigades. Grannies for Peace's first event was a demonstration at the Albany Military Recruiting Office in Colonie Center Mall on February 14, 2006.
Additional information about the organization can be found on Women Against War's archived website, http://womenagainstwar.org/Archive/index.htm.
Related Materials
Related collections include the Eleanor Stein Papers (apap383). Stein, a lawyer and environmental activist, was a founding member of Women Against War.
Content Description
The physical materials in the collection include meeting minutes, correspondence, membership lists, fliers, journals, photographs, newspaper clippings, publications, and A/V documenting the activities of Women Against War. Particularly well-represented are the records from the 2002/2003 Women's Fast For Peace, including journal entries by each participant; the meeting minutes, correspondence, and events for the projects Grannies for Peace and Pathways to Peace; and the meeting minutes of the Steering Committee. The digital materials in the collection include the Waging Peace Wordpress Blog, which appeared on the Albany Times Union website from 2008-2021, interviews with three longtime members, and Yahoo Groups email correspondence from 2002 to 2021.
Women Against War; Peace movements--New York (State); Women and peace--New York (State); Antinuclear movement--New York (State).; Women; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Senior Citizens; Iraq War, 2003-2011; Blog authorship; Albany, New York; Correspondence; Minutes; Newsletters; Political posters
- Activist Toolkit: An Introductory Guide to Social Justice Activism in the Capital Region, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Afghanistan: Classical Benefit Concert, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Afghanistan: Parker School, 2009; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Afghanistan Project, 2008-2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Afghanistan Project, 2010-2013 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Afghanistan: Understanding the Issues Event, 2009; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Against War with Iraq, the Center for Constitutional Rights, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Annual Gathering, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Annual Gathering, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Annual Gathering, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Annual Gathering, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Annual Gathering, 2016-2017 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Annual Gathering, 2017-2018 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Annual Gathering, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Annual Gathering, 2019-2020 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Anti-War Billboard Launch, 2017-2018; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Bethlehem Neighbors for Peace "Peace Now" Discussion with Trudy Quaif, Maud Easter and Mabel Leon, 2013
- Beyond Afghanistan / No Drones Project, 2013-2014; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Beyond Afghanistan / No Drones Project, 2016-2017 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Blog, 2008-2009; 2013; 2015; 2017-2020 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Climate, 2007; 2019; Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Code Pink Correspondence, 2007-2009; 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Code Pink: Medea Benjamin, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Code Pink Meeting, 2007; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Code Pink: Sheriff's Order, 2020 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- "Diane Reiner on Billboard WRPI 8/19/07", 2007 (Cassette 1)
- Drones, 2009; 2012-2013; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Education for Action Committee, 2002-2007 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Email List, 2005-2007; 2015; Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Events, 2002-2003; 2008; 2016-2017; Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Events, 2011-2017 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Events: Bill Hartung, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Events: Christine Ahn, 2017-2018; 2023; Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Events: Fahima Vorgetts, 2008-2010 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Events: Kathy Kelly, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Events: Kristele Young, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Events: Linda Bilmes, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Events: Malala Joya, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Events: Marjorie Cohn, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Events: Medea Benjamin, 2023 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Events: Miriam Pemberton, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Events: Nick Turse, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Events: Pat Hynes, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Events: Phyllis Bennis, 2017; Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Events: Rafia Zakaria, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Events: Stephen Kinzer, 2014; Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Events: Tim Shorrock, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Eyes Wide Open: Exhibit, 2006; Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Eyes Wide Open: Faith Leadership, 2002; 2006; Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Eyes Wide Open: Poetry, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Eyes Wide Open: Possible Venues, 2006; Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Facebook Page, 2012; 2016; Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Fast for Peace, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Fast for Peace: Cards for Fasters, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Fast for Peace: Fasters' Journal 1, 2002-2003 (Oversize 1)
- Fast for Peace: Fasters' Journal 2, 2003 (Oversize 1)
- Fast for Peace: Fasters' Journal, Faster #73 Original, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Fast for Peace: Fasters' Journal Photocopy, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Fast for Peace: Footage, 2002-2003 (Vhs 1)
- Fast for Peace: Information for Fasters, 2002-2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Fast for Peace: Poster, Undated (Flat-file 1)
- Fast for Peace: Press Conference, 2002 (Vhs 2)
- Fliers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Flower in the Gun Newsletter, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Founding Documents, 2002; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Grannies for Peace: Action Day, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Grannies for Peace: "Capital Outsider Show 22, 3/25/06", 2006 (Dvd 1)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2020 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2021 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Grannies for Peace: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, and Events, 2022-2023 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Grannies for Peace: Counter-Recruitment, 2005-2008; Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Grannies for Peace: Events, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Grannies for Peace: Joan Wile and Barbara Walker, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Grannies for Peace: Lobbying, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Grannies for Peace: Membership Lists, 2007; 2016-2017; Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Grannies for Peace: Mother's Day, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Grannies for Peace: Stewart's Campaign, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Grannies for Peace: Tax Day, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Grannies for Peace: Valentine's Day, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Grannies for Peace: Veteran's Advocacy, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Grannies for Peace: Video Games Project, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Ground the Drones Quilt Project, 2014; Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Grounded by George Brant, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Humanize, Not Militarize Exhibit, 2016-2017; Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Immigration and Naturalization Services (INS) Special Registration, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Indymedia War and Peace Trilogy, Undated (Cd 2)
- International Women's Day, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- International Women's Day, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- International Women's Day, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Interview: Connie Houde, 2013
- Interview: Mickie Lynn, 2015
- Interview: Pat Beetle, 2014
- Iran: Danny Postel, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Iran: Fellowship of Reconciliation Delegation, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Iran: Flyer Committee, 2007-2008; Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Iran: Judy Bello, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Iran Project, 2007-2011 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Iran Project (1 of 2), 2011-2014 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Iran Project (2 of 2), 2011-2014 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Iran Project, 2014-2019 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Iran Project, 2021-2023 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Iran: Times Union Meeting, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Iran: Trita Parsi, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Iraq: Card Project, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Iraq: Fifth Anniversary, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Iraq: Leafletting Project, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Iraq: Manna Jo Green, 2003; Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Iraq: Names Project, 2004-2006 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Iraq: Nine Parts of Desire by Heather Raffo Manuscript, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Iraq: Refugee Project, 2007-2011 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Iraq: Walking Memorial, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Jim Perry Progressive Leadership Awards, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Korea: Events, 2013; 2018; Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Korea: Hyun Lee Event, 2021-2022 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Legislative Committee, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Legislative Committee, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Letters to Editor / Op-Eds, 2005; 2013; 2021-2022 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Lobbying our Legislators on Nuclear Weapons, 2021; Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Madre: An International Women's Human Rights Organization, 2002; Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Media, 2006-2008; 2011-2012; 2018; Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Media Clippings, 2007-2010; 2013; 2015; 2018 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Media Committee, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Media Committee, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Meeting Minutes, 2002-2007 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Meeting Minutes and Communications, 2002-2005; 2012; Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Meetings: Antonio Delgado, 2019-2022; Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Meetings: Chris Gibson, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Meetings: Chuck Schumer, 2011-2015; 2018-2023 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Meetings: Kirsten Gillibrand, 2009-2015; 2019-2022 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Meetings: Paul Tonko, 2008-2015; 2018-2023 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Meetings: Scott Murphy, 2009; Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Middle East Actions, 2006-2011 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Military Contractors, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Mother's Day, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Multimedia Committee, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- National Organization for Women Conference, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Nominating Committee, 2006-2009 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Organizational Notes, 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Our Town, 2010; Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Pathways to Peace, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Pathways to Peace, 2018 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Pathways to Peace, 2019 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Pathways to Peace, 2020 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Pathways to Peace, 2021 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Pathways to Peace, 2022 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Pathways to Peace, 2023 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Pathways to Peace: De-Militarization of Police, 2014; 2020-2021; Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Patriot Act Events, 2003-2004; 2006; Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Peace Protest, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Peace Tent, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Photographs, 2006; Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Posters, Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
- "Priscilla Fairbank Interviewed about Iran Trip WRPI 12/20/07" (Cassette 2)
- "Priscilla Fairbank Iran Interview WRPI 11/29/07", 2007 (Cassette 3)
- Publications: Afghan Women's Health, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Publications: Edward Said, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Publications: June Jordan, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Publications: Martin Luther King, Jr. and Coretta Scott King, Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Publications: Miscellaneous, 2001-2003; Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Publications: The Politics of Oil, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Publications: War on Terror and Iraq War, 2001-2003; Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Resist: Grant Funding Application, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Reunion and Open House, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Sign Campaign, 2015; Undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Solidarity Network, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Songsheets, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Steering Committee, 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Steering Committee, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Steering Committee, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Steering Committee, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Steering Committee, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Steering Committee, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Steering Committee, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Steering Committee, 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Steering Committee, 2016-2017 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Steering Committee, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Steering Committee, 2019 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Steering Committee, 2020 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Steering Committee, 2021 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Steering Committee, 2022-2023 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Tenth Anniversary, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- UN Secretary General's Report on Women, Peace, and Security, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Vigils, 2009; Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- "Voices for Creative Nonviolence: Community Responses to War", 2009 (Cd 3)
- "WAMC Rountable Billboard Segment Diane Reiner 8/6/07", 2007 (Dvd 1)
- Waging Peace WordPress Website, 2008 June 30 - 2021 February 04
  - Cooking Up Peace, 2008 June 30
  - Signs of Peace Blooming in Washington Park, 2008 July 10
  - Hope, 2008 July 7
  - Peace Ingredients From the Community Pantry, 2008 July 19
  - Trying to create a small opening for diplomacy, 2008 August 5
  - Finding A Guiding Star in Times of War, 2008 August 6
  - Encouraging Day for "No War on Iran" Efforts, 2008 August 8
  - The Real Danger of War, 2008 August 11
  - Report from Otsego County Fairgoers Against Iran War, 2008 August 8
  - Sexual Violence in the US Military, Dateline: Iraq and Kuwait, 2003 to 2008, 2008 August 14
  - Rights and Responsibilities, 2008 August 16
  - New Party Games!, 2008 August 21
  - A Trained Warrior Wages Peace With Joy and Determination, 2008 August 19
  - That Old War Song Keeps Georgia on my Mind, 2008 August 27
  - Another, Briefer Article About Georgia, From Malaysia, 2008 August 27
  - Saving the World and Ourselves, 2008 August 28
  - Silver Lining, 2008 August 23
  - "I told them I lived in the virtue of that life and power that took away the occasion of all wars" -- George Fox, 2008 September 2
  - Salaam, Shalom, Solh, Paz, Peace, 2008 August 30
  - Sometimes We Settle for "Better Late than Never", 2008 September 4
  - Women Could End War In 1 day!, 2008 August 29
  - Don't Fight, Indict!, 2008 September 12
  - Waging Peace One Person at a Time, 2008 September 6
  - Violence is easy. Take the "waging peace" challenge, 2008 September 15
  - how we use words, 2008 September 9
  - How Do We Define Support?, 2008 September 12
  - What's This About the US Being Attacked?, 2008 September 19
  - A Survivor of War Inspires Me to Wage Peace, 2008 September 20
  - Serial fasting for peace, 2008 September 23
  - Whistle While You Work..for Peace, 2008 September 26
  - No Peace without Justice for Women, 2008 September 28
  - It's never too late to work for peace, 2008 October 1
  - Who is in My Voting Booth?, 2008 October 6
  - What about the warriors?, 2008 October 3
  - A Question of Respect, 2008 October 8
  - Crisis Time: Will We Learn, Talk, & Listen?, 2008 October 13
  - The Warriors, 2008 October 11
  - The UN: Just What the US Needs, 2008 October 20
  - Fall Break in Upstate New York, 2008 October 15
  - The Co$ts of War, 2008 October 17
  - In Pursuit of Information, 2008 October 23
  - War is Warming!, 2008 October 27
  - Alone with your Trusty Radio, 2008 October 25
  - Washington warns Iraq to accept security deal!, 2008 October 29
  - I saw a monster on Madison!, 2008 October 31
  - Will you need to "steal back your vote" tomorrow?, 2008 November 3
  - Please Help Me Understand!, 2008 November 6
  - Words to Express, 2008 November 8
  - Spending something to get change., 2008 November 11
  - A Seat at the Table, 2008 November 15
  - Freedom Is Not Free!, 2008 November 13
  - Shoot Out at the OK Corral. Wait a minute--this isn't a movie!, 2008 November 18
  - A Child Is Born, 2008 November 20
  - Let Them Eat Wonder Bread, 2008 November 25
  - A Community of Learning, 2008 November 22
  - An Attitude of Gratitude!, 2008 November 27
  - Grateful, 2008 November 30
  - The Rich Fabric of Our Society, 2008 December 2
  - "Small Person, Big Principles", 2008 December 4
  - Back in the (bloggin') Saddle, 2008 December 6
  - "Quakers: still here, still for PEACE", 2008 December 9
  - Nature or Nurture, 2008 December 12
  - Icy weekend- warm welcome!, 2008 December 13
  - "Listening, listening, listening", 2008 December 16
  - Class and Society, 2008 December 19
  - Saturnalia to Black Friday, 2008 December 21
  - An all too frequent story, 2008 December 23
  - Transformation, 2008 December 25
  - One-fifth of Us Homeless?, 2009 January 5
  - A New Year's Greeting from Prison, 2008 December 31
  - Holding Power, Withholding Sex, 2009 January 2
  - What do we mean by Justice?, 2009 January 7
  - It's My Life! - A Book Report, 2009 January 15
  - Particles of Faith, 2009 January 11
  - Obama: Be Smart on Afghanistan!, 2009 January 19
  - Remember the Forgotten, 2009 January 21
  - 3 Cheers for Smart Power!, 2009 January 26
  - Torture: A Matter for Discussion?, 2009 January 24
  - Afghanistan Reader, 2009 January 28
  - Carter: Communicate with Unsavory People, 2009 January 31
  - The Endless War, 2009 February 3
  - Landmines and Cluster Bombs: "Terrorism in Slow Motion", 2009 February 5
  - Balance, Perspective and Knowledge, 2009 February 7
  - Christmas Eve 2008, 2009 February 10
  - Valentine's Day, brutality breaks our hearts, 2009 February 12
  - Do Sanctions Against Iran Work?, 2009 February 14
  - How to Fix the Mess, 2009 February 17
  - Sometimes the Medium is the Message, 2009 February 19
  - Diplomatic Relations With Iran - An Essential Tool, 2009 February 21
  - Save the Women!, 2009 February 24
  - Afghan Women's Bill of Rights, 2009 February 26
  - Beware of the Warning, 2009 February 28
  - Peace Where?, 2009 March 3
  - Why Investigate? Reversing the Culture of "Anything Goes", 2009 March 5
  - Soldier Suicides, 2009 March 7
  - Alternate Views, 2009 March 10
  - Rituals of Coming Together, 2009 March 19
  - The Poor Women of Iraq, 2009 March 14
  - Change Wears Many Guises, 2009 March 17
  - Islamic Culture, 2009 March 21
  - Visions Past and Present, 2009 March 23
  - Light a Candle, 2009 March 28
  - That Deja Vu Thing, 2009 March 31
  - Congress: AWOL on Afghanistan?, 2009 April 7
  - While the Internet is Down, 2009 April 4
  - Afghanistan Myopia, 2009 April 14
  - Thank goodness it's Friday, 2009 April 10
  - War Costs Limit Our Economic Choices, 2009 April 21
  - Myopic: I can't help it!, 2009 April 18
  - Why get Defensive?, 2009 April 24
  - Granny Peacemakers Celebrated, 2009 April 30
  - Lessons from the Human Influenza A H1N1 Virus, 2009 May 3
  - Torture: An Overview, 2009 May 7
  - The Bill of Not Our Rights, 2009 May 5
  - Diplomacy Not Bombs: Grannies' Saturday Vigil, 2009 May 8
  - The Original Mother's Day, An Anti-war Holiday, 2009 May 10
  - The Other, 2009 May 12
  - Transform the "War On Gangs" With A PROMISE To Our Youth, 2009 May 16
  - The Enduring Legacy of Torture, 2009 May 21
  - Do Americans Eat Their Young?, 2009 May 19
  - Adding The "Remembering" Back Into Memorial Day, 2009 May 23
  - Non-Violence Begins at Home, 2009 May 26
  - What Is Our Plan In Afghanistan?, 2009 May 31
  - Terms of Engagement, 2009 June 4
  - Remembering Ronald Takaki (1939-2009), 2009 June 9
  - Recent Reports from Iran, 2009 June 7
  - The Human Touch, 2009 June 13
  - Hate and Responsibility, 2009 June 16
  - A Hammer Versus Tweezers, Paint, Saw or Tape, 2009 June 19
  - Watching Iran, 2009 June 21
  - Honesty Against the Law, 2009 June 26
  - July 4th in Afghanistan, 2009 July 3
  - Summer Reading: Recent Children's Books on Human Rights, 2009 June 30
  - Panic and Peace, 2009 July 7
  - Can You Imagine Being a Refugee?, 2009 July 10
  - War, What is it good for?, 2009 July 13
  - GameBoys & Predator Drones, 2009 July 17
  - Women's Rights As Human Rights, 2009 July 20
  - Preventing Accidental War with Iran, 2009 July 24
  - Taking back our "good name" in the International Community of Nations, 2009 July 28
  - Why I'll Vigil on Iran Today, 2009 July 31
  - Holding Hands for Peace?, 2009 August 4
  - Keep the Door to Dialogue Open With Iran. [Our Iran Project leaflet about US Iran Policy], 2009 August 2
  - Justice Begins at Home, 2009 August 26
  - August 6, 1945~~~ And the World Changed!, 2009 August 8
  - We Interrupt This Program, 2009 August 12
  - US Military Bases In Colombia, A Dangerous, Deadly, Destructive Idea, 2009 August 14
  - Helen Mary Caldicott, MD, One Of My Personal Sheroes., 2009 August 22
  - Walls and Windows (restoring the "you" to humanity), 2009 August 29
  - I'm Booked!, 2009 September 2
  - Reality Check, 2009 September 6
  - My Twin: Marge Pellegrino and Journey of Dreams, 2009 September 9
  - Catching Up, 2009 September 14
  - How to Be an Ally, 2009 September 16
  - Roots and Trends, 2009 September 20
  - The Worst Dictator, 2009 September 23